Finding aid to the Alfred Young Papers CA.MS.00160
Smith College Archives
Alfred Young Papers
1890-1935
Smith College Archives
Young, Alfred
CA.MS.00160
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
The papers contain Alfred Young's files on the production of William Shakespeare's plays The Merchant of Venice, Merry Wives of Windsor, A Midsummer Night's Dream and Twelfth Night.
Biographical / Historical
Alfred Young, the stage name of John Carolan, was director of senior Dramatics at Smith College, 1892-1917, with the exception of 1893. He also was involved with directing plays at other colleges and stage venues.
Young was engaged to direct a play chosen by the senior class and with only a few exceptions they were Shakespeare plays. Once the play was chosen, members of Smith College's Dept. of Elocution trained individual actors in their parts. Young would send instructions as to the overall shape of the play and would come to campus for final rehearsals and production.
Scope and Contents
The papers contain Alfred Young's files on the production of William Shakespeare's plays The Merchant of Venice, Merry Wives of Windsor, A Midsummer Night's Dream and Twelfth Night.
The papers are divided into five series:
Series I: General materials
Series II: The Merchant of Venice
Series III: Merry Wives of Windsor
Series IV: A Midsummer Night's Dream
Series V: Twelfth Night
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
80. Class of 1893-1917. Senior Dramatics box
80. Dramatics
"Senior Dramatics," Smith College Weekly (May 15, 1912) 2, no. 30: [1]-2.
"Senior Dramatics," Smith College Weekly (June 10, 1914) 4, no. 24: [1]-2.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Young, Alfred
- Series I: General
  - Correspondence, 1890s-1909 (Box 1106, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1106, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 1935 (Box 1106, Folder 3)
- Series II: The Merchant of Venice
  - Director's copy and prompt book (Box 1106, Folder 1)
  - Smith College production programs and reviews, 1897; 1911 (Box 1106, Folder 2)
  - Programs of production by Alfred Young, 1898 (Box 1106, Folder 3)
  - Programs of productions by other directors, 1910; 1924 (Box 1106, Folder 4)
  - Stage designs (Box 1106, Folder 5)
  - Smith College production notes, 1911 (Box 1106, Folder 6)
  - Other production notes (Box 1106, Folder 7)
  - Clippings on costume and stage design (Box 1106, Folder 8)
- Series III: Merry Wives of Windsor
  - Director's copy and prompt book (Box 1106, Folder 1)
  - Programs and reviews, 1894-1909 (Box 1106, Folder 2)
  - Production notes (Box 1106, Folder 3)
  - Music (Box 1106, Folder 4)
  - Clippings on costume (Box 1106, Folder 5)
- Series IV: A Midsummer Night's Dream
  - Director's copy and prompt books (Box 1107, Folder 1)
  - Programs and reviews (Box 1107, Folder 2)
  - Smith College production notes, 1909 (Box 1107, Folder 3)
  - Hunter College production notes, 1935 (Box 1107, Folder 4)
  - Other production notes (Box 1107, Folder 5)
  - Music (Box 1107, Folder 6)
- Series V: Twelfth Night
  - Director's copy and prompt book (Box 1107, Folder 1)
  - Smith College program and review, 1917 (Box 1107, Folder 2)
  - Programs and reviews of productions by Alfred Young, 1893-1909 (Box 1107, Folder 3)
  - Programs of productions by other directors, 1900s-1910s (Box 1107, Folder 4)
  - Smith College production notes, 1917 (Box 1107, Folder 5)
  - Barnard College production notes, 1909 (Box 1107, Folder 6)
  - Other production notes (Box 1107, Folder 7)
  - State design drawings (Box 1107, Folder 8)
  - Music - Smith College Senior Dramatics, June 1917, Music for Twelfth Night, Pianoforte Score. Boston, Mass.: C. W. Thompson and Co. (Box 1107, Folder 9)
  - Costumes and stage design clippings (Box 1107, Folder 10)
  - Reviews, articles, etc. (Box 1107, Folder 11)